Guide to the Charles Wilkes Papers, 1816-1876 RL.01383
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Wise, Henry Augustus [?] 1849 Feb. 1
Women. Correspondence and Papers 1861-1865
Women. District of Columbia. Washington, 1825[?] Apr. 9
Women. Florida. Pensacola 1846 Jan. 7
Women Travelers 1854 July 26; 1857 (2).
Woodbury, Levi 1834 Dec. 31
Wooster, Charles Whiting 1826 Feb. 4
World Maps Map: 1856 (In Picture Cabinet III-3)
Wright, Frances 1825 Mar. 28
Wright, Richard 1862 Sept. 24
Wright, Silas [?] 1837 May 16
Wyman, Robert Harris 1862 Nov. 30; 1862 Dec. 3; 1862 Dec. 4; 1862 Dec. 28; 1863 Jan. 27; 1863 Jan. 28; 1863 Jan. 30 (2); 1863 Mar. 6; 1863 Mar. 10; 1863 Mar. 20; 1870 Aug. 13; 1870 Aug. 25; 1871 Jan. 22.
Wyman, Thomas W. 1848 Aug. 3
Young, John A. 1867 Aug. 30; 1868 Feb. 26; 1870 July 15; 1870 July 27; 1870 Nov. 8.
Zach, Franz Xaver, Baron Von, 1836 Nov. 3
Zodiacal Light 1857 Nov. 7; 1857 Nov. 12; 1857 Nov. 22; 1857 Dec. 26.
Zoogeography 1850 Nov. 3
Voyages and travels; Industries -- North Carolina; Oregon -- Description and travel; South America -- Discovery and exploration; Explorers -- United States; Gold mines and mining -- North Carolina; Antarctica -- Discovery and exploration; Oceania -- Discovery and exploration; Hawaii -- Description and travel; North Carolina -- Economic conditions; Renwick, James, 1792-1863; United States. Navy -- Officers -- Correspondence; United States Exploring Expedition (1838-1842); Wilkes family; Wilkes, Charles, 1798-1877; Wilkes, Charles, 1798-1877; Wilkes, John, 1827-1908
- Correspondence, 1816-1876
  - 1816-1833 (Box 1)
  - 1834-1837 (Box 2)
  - 1838-1839 (Box 3)
  - 1840-1843 (Box 4)
  - 1844-1847 (Box 5)
  - 1848-1849 Feb. (Box 6)
  - 1849 Mar.-Dec. (Box 7)
  - 1850 (Box 8)
  - 1851-1852 (Box 9)
  - 1853-1854 (Box 10)
  - 1855-1857 Apr. (Box 11)
  - 1857 May-1859 (Box 12)
  - 1860-1869 (Box 13)
  - 1870-1876 (Box 14)
- Legal Materials, 1827-1865 and undated
  - Memorandum, ca. 1848 May 9 (Box 15)
  - Memorandum, 1848[?] (Box 15)
  - Supreme Court, County of Oneida, Summons, 1861 Oct. 7 (Box 15)
  - Untitled Legal Papers, 1827-1865 and undated, 28 Documents (Box 15)
  - Lot Maps, undated, 4 Documents (Box 15)
- Financial Materials, 1830-1875 and undated
  - Untitled Financial Papers, 1830-1875 and undated, 37 Documents (Box 15)
- Printed Material, 1849-1874
  - List of Books, 1849 (Box 15)
  - Working of Gold Mines in New Granada, 1852 May 22 (Box 15)
  - Map of the City of Zanesville, 1855 Mar., No Map Included (Box 15)
  - Prospectus of the American Review, 1855 Nov. 1 (Box 15)
  - Bristol Ferry House, 1856[?] (Box 15)
  - Philadelphia Stock Exchange Sales, 1863 May 4 (Box 15)
  - H.R. 535, 1864 June 18 (Box 15)
  - Siege of Suffolk.---Chancellorsville., 1864 Sept. 20 (Box 15)
  - H.R. 801, 1865 Mar. 1 (Box 15)
  - Report on the High Shoals property in Gaston County, North Carolina, 1873 May 5 (Box 15)
  - Annual Record of Science and Industry, 1874 (Box 15)
  - Woodward and Lothrop, undated, Envelope (Box 15)
  - Untitled Printed Material, 1854 July 12 and undated, 4 Documents (Box 15)
- Clippings and Miscellany, 1825-1875 and undated
  - The Exploring Expedition Publication, 1862 Mar. 1 (Box 15)
  - Portrait of Explorer Wilkes Treasured Here, undated (Box 15)
  - Joint Committee opn the Library of Congress, 1832 June 14 (Box 15)
  - The Results of the U.S. Exploring Expedition Commanded by Capt. Charles Wilkes, 1857 Dec. 26 (Box 15)
  - Revised numbering for the Botanical Map, 1858 Mar. 15 (Box 15)
  - Proposed new numbering (for the Mammalia Map), 1858[?] (Box 15)
  - Proposed new numbering (for map of fhuriatile[?] animals), 1858[?] (Box 15)
  - Additional lettering (for the map of Ground Mammalia), 1858[?] (Box 15)
  - Ammendments to be added to the Bill, 1862[?] (Box 15)
  - Silhouette Card, undated (Box 15)
  - Untitled Documents, 1825-1875 and undated, 44 Documents (Box 15)
  - Cover and Letterpress Book Indices, 1836-1869, 10 Items (Box 15)
- Writings, 1862-1863 and undated
  - Naval Reform, 1862[?] (Box 15)
  - Abuses of the Navy, 1862[?] (Box 15)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 15)
  - Fire Departments, undated (Box 15)
  - Courts and Administration, undated (Box 15)
  - Railways, undated (Box 15)
  - Churches, undated (Box 15)
  - Population of New York, undated (Box 15)
  - Commerce of New York, undated (Box 15)
  - Crotan Water Works, undated (Box 15)
  - Theaters, undated (Box 15)
  - Greenwood Cemetery, undated (Box 15)
  - Hotels, undated (Box 15)
  - [Trip to the Far West?] Chapter XVII, undated (Box 15)
  - [Trip to the Far West?] Chapter XVIII, undated (Box 15)
  - The Great International Question, undated (Box 15)
  - The Surrender of Mason and Slidell, undated (Box 15)
  - Iron Clad Vessels, undated (Box 15)
  - Trip to the Far West, 1863, 2 Folders (Box 15)
  - In difesa del San Giacinto, 1862 Feb. 14 (Box 15)
- Volumes, 1823-1847
  - Notes related to Fejee Islands, 1840 July 15-Aug. 7 (Box 16)
  - Account Book for Ship O'Cain, 1823 (Box 16)
  - Charles Wilkes, Financial Log Books, 1828-1830, 1833, 3 Volumes (Box 16)
  - Edmund Wilkes, 1847 (Box 16)
  - "Map of the World shewing [sic] the Extent and Direction of the Wind and the Route To Be Followed in a Circumnavigation of the Globe" by Charles Wilkes, 1856, and a broadside, including a plat of several lots of Charles Wilkes' land in Washington, D. C. for sale, May 12, 1874. (Oversize-folder 1)